行尸走肉前情回顾
Previous on AMC's The Wlaking Dead.
别伤害我女儿
Don't hurt my little girl.
不!
No!
- 你假装自己是州长  - 你没看到你身边的魔鬼吗?
- And you pretend to be you are a governor.  - Haven't you see the devil beside you?
我已经看到了
I've seen him already.
我得和你谈谈Carel
I need to talk to you about Carol.
都听我的
I'm in charge. No dead win.
和Michelle在一起你得多想想
In the world of Michelle you gotta think.
也许我们能找到一个更好的地方
Maybe we can find a better place.
我要劝你们做些事
I have to talk all of you into doing something.
不得不做的事
Something I know we need to do.
可我不知道该怎么说
And I don't know how to talk about it.
你想要我们做什么?
What do you want us to do?
我要你们活下去
I want you to survive.
我们不能在这待下去了
We're not gonna last here.
会有成群的行尸
The biters, there'll be a herd of them.
他们会把坑填平
They'll fill the pits,
从同伴身上爬过去
they'll crawl over one another.
足以把我们的营地踏平
There'll be enough to tear right through our camp.
也许还会是人
Or it'll be people.
我们和外界之间已经没有阻碍了
There's nothing between us and the rest of the world.
完全没有
Nothing between us and them.
留在这儿 我们就只有死路一条
We stay here, we'll die.
破坏了我在Martinez营地的人
The people who destroyed the camp I was in with Martinez...
他们住在一个监狱里
they live in a prison.
在34号公路的北侧
It's north off Highway 34.
他们有墙
They got walls...
篱笆
fences,
可以种植的土地
plots of land for farming.
我们可以住在那
We could live there.
哼哼
Uh-uh.
如果我们要从他们手里夺过来
If we're willing to take it from 'em.
我有一个不必伤害任何人的计划
I have a plan to do it without anyone getting hurt.
我抓住了两个
I captured two of them.
什么?
What?
当时我正在搜查监狱
I was scouting the prison
结果就遇到了 于是我抓了他们
and our paths crossed, so I took 'em.
- 你抓住了他们?  - 他们是关键人物
- You took them?  - They're the key.
他们会帮我们不费一枪一弹地夺下那个监狱
They're gonna help us take that prison without firing a shot.
我们可以占领监狱 而且不必杀掉任何人
We can have it and we don't need to kill anyone.
但是...
But...
我们得准备好
we need to be prepared to.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 波特妹子 时间轴: 潇妹纸
翻译: yjk8654 初见 失眠影
校对: 潇妹纸
行尸走肉 第四季 第八集
这个监狱里的不都是坏人
The people in this prison, not all of them are bad.
但大多数都是小偷
But most of them are thieves,
或者杀人犯
murderers.
为什么那样的人每天都平安无事
Now why should people like that have peace of mind
可我们每天都要埋掉同伴?
when we're burying our own just about every day?
这些人把我弄伤...
These people, they mutilated me...
烧了我的营地...
burned my camp...
还杀了我女儿
killed my daughter.
你们看到了... 我尽力了
Now you saw me... I tried.
我曾想过去死
I tried to die.
因为我不想接受命运安排
'Cause I didn't want to accept that you couldn't live
不想靠屠戮别人来生存
in this world without getting blood on your hands.
现在找到了你们 我又想活下去
I found you people and I don't want to die.
我不希望你们死去
I don't want you to die.
现在我们该行动了
Now we need to move... now.
他们会发现自己人失踪了
They're gonna realize their people are gone
他们会为接下来发生的事做好准备
and they're gonna start getting ready for whatever's next.
我们要出其不意 让他们恐惧
We need to surprise them. Scare them.
怎么样?
Huh?
我们会赢的
And we will win.
我加入
I'm in.
- 我加入  - 我也是
- I'm in.  - Me, too.
收拾东西 准备出发
Pack up and get ready.
半小时后部署计划
We'll go over the plan in half an hour.
- 来吧  - 我们走
- Come on.  - Let's do it.
Megan呢?
Where's Megan?
在车里看书
She's reading in the trailer.
你都听见了?
You hear all that?
我们没必要为了别的住所而开战
I said we didn't have to fight for another place.
我知道
I know.
要杀人?
Killing people?
不 以暴制暴
No. Killing killers.
你说他们不都是坏人
You said they weren't all bad people.
可他们和坏人在一起
Well, they're with bad people.
我也是吗?
Am I?
我会让你活下去
I'm gonna keep you alive.
我会让Megan活下去
I'm gonna keep Megan alive.
唯一对我重要的事就是
The only judgment on me I care about
你们俩是否还活着
is whether you two are still breathing.
你能听见很好
It's good that you heard,
能明白更好
that you know.
Lily... 我爱你
Lily... I love you.
我看不透你了
I don't know who you are.
你说有更好的地方
Hey, you told me there has to be someplace better
而我在帮你找到它
and that I was gonna help you find it.
你懂我的 Lily
You knew me, Lily.
一切都不会变的
It was always gonna be like this.
你也得收拾东西了
You need to pack up, too.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
放开我
Get off me.
吃点东西 这一天会很漫长
You should eat. It's gonna be a long day.
没人会伤害你们
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
我不相信
I don't believe that.
是吗 我可不在乎
Well, I don't care.
告诉我这是为什么
Just tell us what this is.
求你了
Please.
无关个人恩怨
It isn't personal.
那是怎么回事?
Then what is it?
Michonne 我希望你知道...
Michonne, I want you to know...
我的女儿Penny
Penny, my daughter,
她早死了 我现在懂了
she was dead. I know that now.
我不想伤害你
Now, I don't want to hurt you.
我不想伤害任何人
I don't want to hurt anyone.
我只想要那座监狱
I need the prison, that's it.
我有我要守护的人
There are people I need to keep alive.
你俩将是我夺回监狱的筹码
You two are gonna help me take it.
没有人会死
No one needs to die.
我要杀了你
I'm gonna kill you.
你不会的
No, you won't.
- 我要用我...  - 别说了
- I'm gonna take my...  - Stop it.
你想要那座监狱？
You want the prison?
是的 尽量和平
Yeah. And I'll take it as peacefully as I can.
- 总督...  - 别叫我总督
- Governor...  - Don't call me that.
你的人和我们的人
Your people, our people,
我们可以找到共同生存的办法
we can find a way to live together.
你要守护的这些人
These people you need to keep alive,
你爱他们吗?
do you love them?
Hershel 你是个好人
You're a good man, Hershel.
比Rick好
A better man than Rick.
你说的这些事 还有你说的方式
Everything you've said, the way you've said it,
你已经变了 Rick也一样
you've changed. So has Rick.
我们俩不会在一起生活
The two of us will never be able to live together.
我和Michonne永远不会在一起生活
Michonne and I, we'll never be able to live together.
- 一定能想出办法  - 我找到了办法!
- We'll find a way.  - I found a way!
我很努力了
I'm trying hard.
想夺回监狱有许多方式
There's all kinds of ways I could do this.
而选这种方式 你们会活下去 我会...
This way, you get to live and I get to be...
你说你会尽量和平地
You say you want to take this prison
夺下这座监狱
as peacefully as possible.
也就是说为了夺下它 你会伤害别人
That means you'd be willing to hurt people to get it.
我的女儿也在那
My daughters would be there.
你会伤害她
That's who you'd be hurting.
如果你能理解一个父亲的感受
If you understand what it's like to have a daughter,
怎么还会去伤害别人的女儿?
then how can you threaten to kill someone else's?
因为那不是我的女儿
Because they aren't mine.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
- 拿着  - 好的
- Here, take this.  - Okay.
我们回来之前 他们会很安全
They'll be safe here until we get back.
行尸们过不了这条河
Biters can't make it across the water.
既然在河边会安全 何不去河边找一个地方
If it's safe by the water, then let's just go someplace by the water.
- Lily  - 你不必这么做
- Lily.  - You don't have to do this.
所有真正安全的地方
Anyplace that's safe, really safe,
都被人捷足先登了
someone's already there.
想想Megan吧 好吗？
Think about Megan, huh?
我在想
I am.
在这样的环境里 她怎么办?
What's she gonna be in this world?
她会活得好好的
She's gonna be alive.
在做泥浆馅饼?
Making mud pies?
是奶油花生三明治
Peanut butter sandwiches.
来个临别拥抱怎么样?
How about a hug before I go?
我手上都是泥巴 看到了吗?
My hands are muddy. See?
哦 是啊
Oh, yeah.
我可不想弄脏我的外套
Well, I wouldn't want to get my coat dirty.
我把它弄脏了
I messed it all up.
不 你让它更好看了
No, you made it better.
我好不容易休次假
I could use a vacation.
别打扰我
Get away.
两天就行
Just for a weekend.
好的
Yeah.
我们的纪念日要到了
You know, our anniversary is coming up.
是吗?
It is?
就差几天
One of these days.
你去过大瀑布吗?
You ever been to Amicalola Falls?
乔治亚州最大的瀑布
Tallest waterfall in Georgia.
- 没有  - 小时候我爸带我去过
- Mm-mmm.  - My dad took me there when I was little.
到了顶部之后
When we were up there,
从上面往下看
all the way at the top looking down,
感觉就像在飞一样
I felt like I was flying.
我这就去套上马车
I'll go load up the station wagon.
我去给你拿点水
I'm gonna get you some water.
- 我自己能拿  - 我知道
- I can get it.  - I know.
但我想给你拿
But I'm doing it.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
你就不能等到我们回来吗?
Man, you couldn't have waited till we got back?
等到Tyreese也回来?
Until Tyreese got back?
那我也能对付得了
I could've handled that.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
她杀了两个我们自己人
She killed two of our own.
她不能留在这里
She couldn't be here.
她不会有事的
She's gonna be all right.
她有车 有补给品 有武器
She has a car, supplies, weapons.
她知道如何生存
She's a survivor.
你不要自欺欺人了
Stop saying that like you don't believe it.
她杀了人 说是为了我们
She did it. She said it was for us.
她确实是那么想的
That's how it was in her head.
她一点也不愧疚
She wasn't sorry.
没错 她做了 但她是迫不得已
Man, that's her, but that ain't her.
我们要怎么处置那两个女孩?
What are we supposed to do about those two girls?
我答应她要照顾她们
I told her we'd look after them.
我还没告诉Tyreese
I haven't told Tyreese yet.
不知道他会有什么反应
I don't know how he's gonna take it.
走去试试吧
Let's go find out.
等等 Bob
Bob.
你应该去休息
You should be resting.
昨晚那么累 你也应该休息
After the night you had, so should you.
我正想去休息
I'm going to.
我打算先去C区找个空房间
On my way to find an open cell in C block
直到D区被打扫干净
until D gets cleaned up.
我想告诉你
I just wanted to say
谢谢你
thank you.
如果没有你和Hershel 我不知道
I wouldn't be here if it wasn't for Hershel
自己会在哪里
and you.
你应该谢Hershel 别谢我
Hershel, not me.
- 你也帮忙救了我  - 别说了
- You helped save my life.  - Stop.
- Bob  - 别说了
- Bob.  - Stop.
你把药物加到了我的输液袋
You put those meds in my IV bag.
所以现在的我
And now, in a couple minutes,
才能再次见到阳光
I'm gonna feel the sun on my skin.
所以我必须要谢谢你
So you are gonna let me thank you.
Sasha啊
Sasha.
你还很虚弱
You're not strong enough yet.
那就帮帮我
Then help me.
Tyreese 你在吗?
Tyreese. You down here?
Rick 是你吗?
Rick, that you?
你们一定要看看这个
You guys got to see this.
能等会再看吗? 我们想和你说点事情
Can we take a beat? There's something we need to talk about.
不能等 快过来
It can wait. Come on.
看
Look.
什么东西?
The hell?
刚刚我正在找...
I was just looking for...
原因...
answers...
然后就发现了这个
and I found this.
与杀死Karen和David的是同一个人
Same person that killed Karen and David did this.
还记得篱笆那里的老鼠吗?
Remember the rats at the fence?
她死的那天老鼠也出现了
They showed up the same day she was killed.
这里住着一个神经病
We got a psychopath living with us.
- Tyreese  - 得把他抓住 Rick
- Tyreese.  - We got to find him, Rick.
要不然我可不敢闭眼睡觉
And I'm not gonna sleep until we do.
Tyreese啊...
Tyreese...
杀死老鼠的
whoever did this,
和杀死Karen的不是同一个人
I don't think that's who killed Karen.
你怎么知道?
Why?
快走
Come on.
躲好!
Get back!
Rick啊!
Rick!
过来
Come down here.
我们谈谈
We need to talk.
我说的不算
It's not up to me.
这里的委员会才能做决定
There's a council now. They run this place.
Hershel是委员会成员吗?
Is Hershel on the council?
Michonne是吗?
What about Michonne?
她也是委员会成员?
She on the council, too?
这里不是我说的算了
I don't make decisions anymore.
今天就是你说了算 Rick
You're making the decisions today, Rick.
过来
Come down here.
我们谈谈吧
Let's have that talk.
我们能行的 明白吗?
We can do this. All right?
我们没法对付那么多人
We can't take 'em all on.
我们首先穿过指挥大楼
We'll go through the admin building,
再按计划穿过树荫
through the woods like we planned.
我们的人数已经没有优势了
We ain't got the numbers no more.
上次检查汽车上的藏身之处是什么时候?
When's the last time someone checked the stash on the bus?
在我们去Big Spot搜寻物资的前一天
Day before we hit the Big Spot.
那时我们的给养就不足 现在更少了
We were running low on rations then. We're lower now.
会有办法的 如果有情况
Yeah, we'll manage. Things go south,
就让大家都上车 你去通知大家
everyone heads for that bus. Let everybody know.
如果大家不知道情况发生呢?
What if everybody doesn't know when things go bad?
我们能等多久?
How long do we wait?
尽量等吧
As long as we can.
快把他们放了
Let 'em go right now.
我留在这里
I'll stay down here.
你想说什么都行
Talk as long as you want.
但要先把他们放了
But you let 'em go.
你们都有坦克了 不需要人质
You got a tank. You don't need hostages.
需要
I do.
坦克只是为了让你们知道 我是玩真的
This is just to show you I'm serious.
但我不想在我的新家上开个洞
Not to blast a hole in our new home.
太阳下山之前 你和他们撤出这里
You and your people, you have till sundown to get out of here
否则他们就没命了
or they die.
必须要这样吗
Doesn't have to go down this way.
我们人数更多 火力更强
I got more people, more firepower.
我们想要这座监狱
We need this prison.
就这么简单
There it is.
这跟以前的恩怨无关 只与现在有关
It's not about the past. It's about right now.
这里有孩子啊
There are children here.
其中几个孩子病了 要是转移 他们就活不了
Some of them are sick. They won't survive.
我有坦克
I have a tank.
还放你们离开
And I'm letting you walk away from here.
还废什么话呢?
What else is there to talk about?
你还好吗?
You good?
嗯
Yeah.
拿着
All right.
妈咪 你能来帮我挖吗?
Mommy, can you please help me dig?
妈咪 帮我一下嘛
Mommy, can you please help me?
我这就来 宝贝
I'll be right there, honey.
妈咪 好重啊
Mommy, it's too heavy.
听到了 马上就来
I hear you. I'll be there in a sec.
抱歉 宝贝 你刚刚说什么?
I'm sorry, honey. What did you say?
没事了 我自己能行
It's okay. I can do it myself.
Megan! Megan啊!
Megan! Megan!
妈咪! 妈咪!
Mommy! Mommy!
妈咪!
Mommy!
Megan啊!
Megan!
我可以把你们打死
I could shoot you all.
你们会还击 我知道
You'd all shoot back. I know that.
但胜利会属于我们 你们会死
But we'll win and you'll be dead.
一个不剩
All of you.
不一定非要走到那一步
Doesn't have to be like that.
就像我说的 看你们怎么选了
Like I said, it's your choice.
响声只会招致更多的行尸
Noise will only draw more of them over.
等得越久
The longer you wait,
你们离开时越不容易
the harder it will be for you to get out of here.
我们得采取点措施
We got to do something.
你爸爸正在想办法
Your dad's got it.
他们只是在谈话
They're talking.
我们应该立即干掉总督
We could kill the Governor right now.
- 从50码之外?  - 我是个神枪手
- From 50 yards?  - I'm a good shot.
我可以让他一枪毙命
I could end this right now.
要是没打中我们就惨了
Yeah, or you could start something else.
你要相信他
You got to trust him.
你们要去哪里?
Where are you guys going?
- 去车上 一起走吧  - 不
- To the bus. Come on.  - No.
你知道的 我们得按照计划赶紧过去
You know the plan. That's where we're supposed to go.
Carol告诉我们要坚强
Carol told us to be strong.
我们要保护自己 他们有枪
To protect ourselves. They have guns.
我们也应该有枪
We should have guns, too.
我们应该去帮忙
We should help.
距离太阳下山还有半个小时
You got maybe about an hour of sunlight left.
我建议你们快去收拾收拾
I suggest you start packing.
拖得越久
The longer you wait,
离开的时候越艰难
the harder it's gonna be for you to get out of here.
我们...
We can all...
我们可以共享监狱
we can all live together.
这里的房间足够所有人用
There's enough room for all of us.
我知道房间足够
More than enough.
但我的家人如果和你们共处一室
But I don't think my family would sleep well
他们晚上会睡不安稳的
knowing that you were under the same roof.
我们可以去别的区域住
We'd live in different cell blocks.
我们可以不用碰面
We'd never have to see each other
除非你想
till we're all ready.
这个方法可行
It could work.
你知道的
You know it could.
本来是可以的
It could've.
但现在不行了
But it can't.
在伍德伯里事件发生之后
Not after Woodbury.
在Andrea遭遇了那些之后
Not after Andrea.
我知道那样不容易
Look, I'm not saying it's gonna be easy.
我知道那比站在这里
Fact is, it's gonna be a hell of a lot harder
互相射击要难得多
than standing here shooting at each other.
但我们别无选择
But I don't think we have a choice.
我们是没的选 但你们有的选
We don't. You do.
我们不会离开的
We're not leaving.
如果你逼我们 我们就还击
You try and force us, we'll fight back.
如你所言
Like you said,
枪声只会引来更多的行尸
the gunshots will just bring more of them out.
他们会压翻篱笆
They'll take down the fences.
没有篱笆 这里毫无用处
Without the fences, this place is worthless.
要么就一起住在这座监狱
Now, we can all live in the prison
要么大家都别想住
or none of us can.
我来搞定这破篱笆
We'll fix the damn fences.
不...!
No...!
你 那个扎马尾的小姑娘
You. You in the ponytails.
这是你想要的结果吗? 你们要的就是这样吗?
Is this what you want? Is this what any of you want?
你们想要的和我们一样
What we want is what you got.
我们要的 就是你们的所有
至少现在是
Period.
你该走了 混蛋
Time for you to leave, asshole.
听着 我以前和他争过
Look, I fought him before.
但之后 我们收纳了他的老朋友
And after, we took in his old friends.
他们也变成了领导
They've become leaders in what we have here.
只要你们放下武器
Now you put down your weapons,
走进来...
walk through those gates...
就是我们的一员
you're one of us.
我们都放下芥蒂
We let go of all of it,
不用牺牲任何人
and nobody dies.
所有现在还活着的人
Everyone who's alive right now.
所有撑到了现在的人
Everyone who's made it this far.
我们都为了活下去
We've all done the worst kinds of things
不择手段过
just to stay alive.
但我们还是会恢复善良本性
But we can still come back.
我们并没有无药可救
We're not too far gone.
我们必须恢复本性
We get to come back.
我知道...
I know...
我们都可以改变
we all can change.
骗子
Liar.
不!
No!
爸爸!
Daddy!
你!
You!
拿起你的武器! 开枪!
Pick up your weapon! Fight, now!
这不对
This isn't right.
- 我们本不应该这么做  - 就应该这么做
- We're not supposed to be doing this.  - We are.
他用剑把一个人的脑袋砍下来了
He chopped a guy's head off with a sword.
我们得待在这儿 太迟了
We have to stay here. It's too late.
听懂了吗?
You understand me?
跟在我身后 如果我们走散了
Stay behind me and if we get separated,
就找个安全的地方躲起来
you just go run somewhere safe and hide.
听懂了吗? 你找个安全的地方躲起来
You hear me? You go someplace safe and hide
等事情结束了 我就去找你 一定会找到你的
and I will find you when this is all over. I will find you.
用车撞开栅栏
Go through the fence in your cars.
拿上枪 我们冲进去
Get your guns, we go in.
杀光他们
Kill them all.
明白! 大家冲进去!
Roger that! Move it!
快!
Go ahead!
我没子弹了
I'm out of ammo.
去巴士那边 我来掩护你
Run for the bus. I'll cover you.
开炮!
Move up!
快! 离开这里!
Go! Get out of here!
- 快上车! 快点!  - Glenn还在里面 我得去救他
- Go, go! Come on!  - Glenn's in there. I have to get him.
- 我和你一起去  - 让大家上车
- I'm going with you.  - Get these people on the bus.
- 准备好开车离开 我马上回来  - 如果你没回来呢?
- Be ready to drive. I'll be right back.  - What if you're not?
- 那就别等我们了  - 我不会抛下你的
- You have to go without us.  - I won't go without you.
Beth 让大家上车 好吗?
Beth, get these people on the bus, okay?
这是你的任务 我们都有任务要完成
It's your job. We've all got jobs to do.
- Glenn!  - 到底发生了什么事?
- Glenn!  - What the hell's going on?
我们得把所有人都撤出去
We have to get everybody out of here.
Beth! Beth呢?
Beth! Where's Beth?
- 她去找你了  - 她去哪儿了?
- She went to find you.  - Where?
我们会找到她的 她会没事的
We'll find her. She'll be okay.
- 不  - 什么? 不行 你不能一个人去
- No.  - What? No, you're not going by yourself.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
嘿 Maggie...
Maggie...
小心右边
On your right.
炸弹!
Grenade!
Sasha! Sasha! 你看到Beth了吗?
Sasha! Sasha! Have you seen Beth?
- 她在车上吗?  - 不 她不在...
- Is she on the bus?  - No. She's...
我们得蹲低一些
We gotta stay down.
拉开我的衬衫 看看有没有子弹射出的伤口
Look inside my shirt. Check my back for an exit wound.
有
Yeah.
那就好 这伤还有救
That's good. We can treat it.
- 但不能在这儿  - 蹲低点 我们得找个安全的地方
- Not here.  - Stay down. We'll find someplace safe.
会有办法的 我们走
We'll figure it out. Come on.
我们得离开这儿
We got to get out of here.
嘿! 我们往那儿走!
Hey! We go that way!
Carl呢?
Carl...?
Carl在哪儿?
Where's Carl?
我不知道
I don't know.
小心手榴弹!
Grenade!
我在找孩子们 想让他们上车
I was trying to find the kids to get them on the bus.
我们得走了 Beth 走吧
We got to go, Beth. We got to go.
嘿 Carl!
Carl!
听到吗!
Carl啊!
Carl!
Carl 听到吗?
Carl?
Judith呢
Judith.
她在哪儿?
Where is she?
我不知道
I don't know.
不
No.
Carl 住手
Carl. Carl.
我们得离开这里
We've got to get out of here.
我们得走了
We've got to go.
结束了 都结束了
It's over. It's over. It's over.
别往回看 Carl
Don't look back, Carl.
一直往前走
Just keep walking.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 波特妹子 时间轴: 潇妹纸
翻译: yjk8654 初见 失眠影
校对: 潇妹纸